♪〜
〜♪
You really did it!
（男Ａ）やってくれたぜ！
You're awesome, Mr. Vash!
（男Ｂ）さすがヴァッシュさんだ
Yay to the outlaw
who saved the city twice!
（男Ｃ）イヨッ！
町を２度も救った賞金首！
（男Ｄ）そういや
犯罪者なんだよな？
Oh, yeah!
He's a criminal, ain't he?
（３人）ワハハハハハッ
C'mon, drink up!
（男Ｅ）さあ 飲んで飲んで
（ヴァッシュ･ザ･スタンピード）
えっ？ あ…
（一同）
一気！ 一気！ 一気！
Chug! Chug! Chug! Chug!
（ヴァッシュ）ぷはーっ！
（一同）イエーイ！
Hi! Enjoying your drink?
（男性）どうだい 飲んでる？
（メリル･ストライフ）
あっ はい 頂いてますわ
Uh, yes, thank you.
Couldn't be drunker!
（ミリィ･トンプソン）
もう バッチリー！
（男性）ええ… えっ
（メリル）アハハ…
He really is
an unusual guy.
しかし不思議な人だよなあ
（男性）
プラントも直って みんなの緊張が
解けたってのもあるけど—
Sure, everybody's less tense
now that the plant is fixed...
...but they're the ones who
tried to kill him for the reward.
賞金巡って
ドンパチやり合ってた相手だぜ
You'd think he'd be more
uncomfortable around them.
普通なら もっと気まずいよな
All he makes is trouble.
事件ばかり起こして—
I think the world would
be better off without him.
いなくなったほうが
せいせいすると思いますわ
（ミリィ）んにゃあー！
I DISAGREE!
I can handle it!!
I am unique...
大丈夫！
なぜなら私の場合(ばやい)—
...for I have a different
stomach for cake and ice cream!
アイスとケーキで入る所が
別々なのらあ…
…食べる
ハハッ この人も不思議だわ
She's kind of unusual too.
（メイドＡ）ダメだわ ヘンリー
It's no good, Henry.
He's out cold.
（メイドＢ）全然 意識ないよ
Guess I gave him a
little too much to drink.
（ヘンリー）
ちょっと飲ませすぎちまったかあ
I'm sorry I called you both
over here for nothing.
悪いな この時期 無理言って—
お前さん方に来てもらったのに
へっ！
シルヴィによろしく伝えてくれ
Say hi to Sylvie for me!
It's really too bad...
でも ちょっと残念
...you don't get a chance to sleep
with a guy like that every day.
（メイドＢ）
あんな男と寝る機会なんて
めったにないのにね
（メイドＡ）じゃあね
- See you.
- Good night, girls!
（ヘンリー）ああ おやすみ！
（ドアが閉まった音）
（ヴァッシュ）うーん
ハア… 少ーし
もったいなかった… かな
I'm regretting it, just a little.
（打ち上げ花火の音）
（ファンファーレ）
Wha? He left?
えっ！ 行っちゃったって？
（汽笛）
Without saying goodbye?!
（トニス）
えっ？ 何にも言わずに？
Hurry up, Milly!
ミリィ 早くしなさい！
He says Mr. Vash
boarded the sand steamer.
あの人 サンドスチームに
乗ったそうです
えっ！ お金が足りませんわ
WHAT?! We don't
have enough money!
Vash!
（トニス）ヴァッシュー！
（子どもたち）おーい！
How could you just
leave like this?!
（トニス）いきなり行くなんて
ひどいじゃんか！
（子どもたち）ヴァッシュー！
Don't give your momma
too much trouble, Tonis!!
あんまり かあちゃん
困らすんじゃねーぞ トニス！
（子どもたち）ヴァッシュー！
Vash!!
（ヴァッシュ）フッ
All right!
I'm finally alone again!
よーし これでようやく
一人に戻れたあ
うっ… おえーっ！ 飲みすぎたあ
I drank too much.
You Vash the Stampede?
（添乗員）あんたが
ヴァッシュ･ザ･スタンピードか？
You sure don't look it.
とても そうには見えねえな
I didn't call for room service.
ルームサービスは頼んでないよ
We're about to go
into Lottenburg Canyon.
（添乗員）そろそろ
ロッテンバーグ渓谷に入る
And?
だから？
You've heard of it, haven't you?
（添乗員）
話には聞いたことがあるだろ？
It's the turf of the biggest,
baddest, most notorious gang...
最強最悪の声高い
バドラド盗賊団の縄張りさ
...the Bad Lad Gang.
If I can get you on guard duty...
あんたが護衛に付くとなりゃ—
...I can charge double fare.
Say you'll do it!
倍の運賃でも商いになるんだ
頼むよ
Now, see here.
（ヴァッシュ）あのね
I am a passenger.
僕は客なの
My life depends on the defenses
of your ship, so don't let me down.
この船の警備体制には
チョー期待してるから よろしくね
おっ お… 待てよ　待てってば！
Wait! Hey, wait!
Geez.
（ヴァッシュ）…ったく
I'd like to travel more quietly.
俺は もっとひっそりと
やっていきたいのに
さてと…
Now...
...to catch some more Z's!
もうひと眠り…
うおっ くっ ぐわあー！
（ヴァッシュの倒れる音）
（カイト）ああっ！
（ヴァッシュ）ぬわああああ！
（カイト）ひえっ しまった！
Oh, shit!
（ヴァッシュ）…って
HOLD IT RIGHT THERE!
待てー！
人に迷惑かけたら
わびんのが筋だろ？
If you give someone trouble,
you're supposed to apologize!!
Dammit... lookit this blood!
チクショウ
見ろ この血を！
You did that to yourself when
you bashed through the vent!!
（カイト）
顔を出したときの傷だろ？
そいつは！
（ヴァッシュ）
おーおー　関節かあ？
What's this, a stranglehold?
That won't work
while you're in midair.
体浮いてっから 痛かねえぞ
（ヴァッシュ）お前 密航者だろ？
You're a stowaway, aren't you?
Yes, sir.
そうなんです
My parents died
when I was very young...
俺 両親に早く死なれて—
...and some distant relatives took
me in, but it was so horrible there!
遠縁の人に
引き取られたんすけど—
そこが ひどいところで—
My drunk aunt hit me, my really
weird uncle kept trying to get me...
アル中のおばさんには
殴られるし—
すごい趣味のおじさんには
狙われるし—
I can escape
if I make it to May.
メインシティまで行けば
逃げられます
If they take me back,
who knows what they'll do to me!
戻されたら
何をされるか分かりません
Please... don't turn me in!
お願いします
どうか 見逃してください
（カイトの泣き声）
（カイト）ダメだ
I'm dead! Nobody's dumb enough
to buy such a lame story!
こんな臭い話
今どき 誰が信じんだよ
It's the worst one
I ever came up with!
我ながら とっさとはいえ
ひどすぎる
よーく分かった つらかったろ？
I understand how you feel.
It must have been hard!
大丈夫だ　僕に任せな
悪いようにはしねえぜ
It's okay, I'm with you!
I won't let anything happen to you!
Whoa! Is this guy for real?!
（カイト）
うっひょー！ マジっすか？
Two bacon-lettuce dogs,
two cartons of milk...
（メリル）
ベーコンレタスドッグが２つ
パック牛乳が２つ
Now, see here.
あのね…
（メリル）プレッツェル４袋に
干しぶどう１(ワン)パック
...four bags of pretzels,
and one pack of raisins.
I'm dying to know why
you guys are here doing this.
なんで君たちが
ここでこんなことしてんのか—
不思議でしようがないんだけど—
Care to share?
教えてくんない？
We didn't have enough money to ride,
so we got part-time jobs here.
旅費が足りなかったから
ここでアルバイトしてるんです
Altogether, that comes to $ $12.75.
しめて
12ダブドル75セスセントですわ
Right.
（ヴァッシュ）は… はい
I'm amazed you can
eat so much after dinner.
夕食あとなのに
よく これだけ食べられますわね
You eat just like a growing boy!
まるで 食べ盛りの
子どもみたいですね
Y-You think so?
えっ そう？
（ヴァッシュとミリィ）
ハハハハハッ
なんて勘してるんだろうね 全く
Yikes, those two are sharp!
Especially the big one!
特に あのデカいほうときたら
My sole salvation is she
doesn't realize how sharp she is.
本人が自覚してねえのが
唯一の救いだよ
Hey, Vash!
（添乗員）あっ ヴァッシュさん
しっかりとガード頼むぜ
無理して部屋とったんだからな
Guard this place well! It wasn't
easy to get you that room, you know.
Yes, boss.
へいへい
Hey, growing boy!
よう 食べ盛りの子どもさん！
Your mouth is silent,
but your eyes are speaking.
おとなしくしてても
目が言ってるぜ
腹ペコで死にそうだってな
They say,
"I'm starving to death!"
Here.
ほれ
うわーっ！
痛(い)ってえ
（カイト）ふーん
ハアア…
（ヴァッシュ）すごい闇だよな
It really is dark.
Not a single light to be seen.
光ひとつ見えない
Oh, yeah?
（カイト）そうかい？
It'll be bright soon enough.
もうすぐ輝くぜ
（ヴァッシュ）あっ！
Sorry about that,
Mr. Goody-Goody.
（カイト）悪いね  お人よし
One more left. I gotta hurry.
あと１つ  急がなきゃ
（ネオン管の放電音）
（電子音）
Hey, Beremy.
（Ｂ.Ｄ.ネオン）ヘイ ベラミィ
Yeah?
（ベラミィ）イエー！
What's our time?
時刻は？
22:53.
（ベラミィ）２２(トゥトゥ) ５３(ファイブスリー)
O.K.
オーケー
Listen up, doggies!
いいか てめえら！
The kid should have
it all set by now.
そろそろ小僧も 仕掛けた頃合いだ
7 minutes until the parade!
Make it good and flashy!
パレードまで あと７分！
派手にきめるぜ
Right on time!
（手下Ａ）
時間ピッタリ 紫の信号筒だ！
It's the purple signal!
All right, let's do it!
（手下Ｂ）よし いくぜー！
Here we go!!
（手下Ａ）ヒア ウィ ゴー！
（手下たち）イエーイ！
おっ？
Captain!
せ… 船長！
（船長）ん？
That's...
あっ あれは！
...the Bad Lad Gang!
バドラド団
What the hell is that?!
（運転手）何だ？ ありゃ
（バドラド団員）
肥臭(くせ)えワゴンにゃ 用はねえ！
We don't need no
pissant cars!
Bastard thieving jerkwads!!
（助手）野郎 武装盗賊団か！
What's the big man doing?!
何してやがんだ ビッグマンは
He's getting paid
to blast these!
追っ払うのも料金のうちだろうが！
Why aren't you firing
the main cannons?!
なぜ主砲を撃たん！
It's no good, sir!
There's no response!
ダメです　応答がありません！
（爆発音）
（メリルとミリィ）
何ご… うっ！ ううっ
What's going...
（メリル）ううっ…
（ミリィ）痛たたた…
（メリル）何事ですの？
What's going on?
（船員）敵襲！
右舷後方のハッチに取りつかれた！
We're under attack!!
They're on the rear starboard hatch!
（発砲音）
（警備員）ぐわああ！
（警備員たちの叫び声）
The ultimate magnificent
dreadnought raiders!
（ネオン）究極華麗弩級(どきゅう)盗賊
Bad Lad Leader!
バドラド団 ヘーッド！
Brilliant Dynamites Neon...
ブリリアント･ダイナマイツ･ネオン
...emerges!
光臨！
（銃声）
Now, all that glitters
in this ship belongs to me!
今から 船内の光り物は
すべて この俺様の物だ
（扉の破壊音）
You worked brilliantly, kid.
輝いた仕事ぶりだぜ 小僧
Now gather all of the
passengers in one spot.
次は客を１か所に集める
Take me to
the party room.
パーティールームへ案内しな
Understood.
わ… 分かった
（女性の歌声）
So...
... on the first evening...
（ヴァッシュ）歌だ…
It's a song.
... a pebble from somewhere...
... drops upon the world.
歌が聞こえる
I hear a song.
So...
... on the second evening...
... the children of the pebble
join hands...
... and compose a waltz.
（レムの笑い声）
（レム）私 ドキドキしている
I'm so excited!
The meaning of life?
生きる意味？
ヴァッシュったら真面目なのね
You're very serious-minded,
aren't you, Vash?
We decide our own destinations.
行き先は自分で決めるの
Rem...
レム…
You're such a baby.
（レム）甘えちゃって
Our tickets to the future are blank.
切符は真っ白なのよ
Please...
お願い
...decide your own destiny...
未来への切符は…
ま… 待ってくれ！ レム
Wait, Rem...
Rem...
レム…
レム！
REM!
（ベッドから落ちる音）
あ…
（扉が開く音）
What?
何だ？
（黒猫の鳴き声）
Crud.
チェ！ これっぽっちかよ
貧乏人ども
Is this all,
you bunch of beggars?
Don't try to fool me!
Where is it?!
…んなはずねえだろ　どこにある？
（客Ａ）うわああ…
Boss!
（手下Ｂ）ヘッド！
（ネオン）ん？
So, they do have one,
and a big one at that.
なんでえ なんでえ
あるじゃねえかよ 立派なやつが
Open it up for me, would you?
ちょちょいと開けてくれ
It isn't possible to!
（船員）不可能だ！
Not a single person on this ship
knows the combination to the safe!
この船に乗る誰ひとりとして—
大金庫の暗証番号は
知らされていない
And besides, the coded
interlocking key is in the city!
それに連動コード式の鍵は
町にある
It's not here!
ここにはない
へっ なるほど よく分かった
I see.
Thanks for telling me.
That means we'll
have to break it open.
ぶっ壊すしかねえってことだな
Once we're around the mountain
to the right, go straight.
右手の山を回り込んだら
そのまま まっすぐ行け
In 5 minutes, when we're within sight
of the canyon, head north-northeast...
５分後 渓谷が見える北北東に
進路を取り 加速を始めろ
...and begin accelerating.
At full speed,
we'll arrive in 10 minutes.
全速力で10分で到着する
目的地は ここ エノラ断崖だ
This is our destination,
the Enora Precipice.
What?!
（船長）何だと？
A-At least let us
unload the passengers!
じょ… 乗客だけは
降ろさせてくれ
頼む！
Please!!
あん？
We risked our lives
to get here.
こっちは命懸けで ここにいるんだ
You should be expected
to risk your lives too.
お前らも命を懸けるのは
当然じゃねえか
You depraved lunatic!
貴様　この外道が！ うっ…
This is the superexpress
to your final blaze of glory!
貧相な人生に
死に花咲かす超特急
If it's not flashy,
what's the point?!
派手に決めなきゃ意味がねえだろ
This is a shocking mess we're in!
（ミリィ）
どえれえことになっちゃいましたね
The two of us can't do anything
against an armed gang.
（メリル）
私たちだけで武装集団相手に
どうすることもできませんわ
The only person who could do
something in this situation...
（ミリィ）この状況を
なんとかできそうな人って…
...is him.
あの人だけでしょうね
Although it pains me
to say it.
思いっきり不本意ですけど
ぐはっ！
どこにいるか分かんないれすよ
But I can't tell where I am!
（衝撃音）
（ミリィ）あっ！
（メリル）何？
What?
（操舵士(そうだし)）ぐっ
うわああああ！
おいおい 何してる
それブレーキじゃないの？
Come on, what are you doing?
Isn't that the brake?
我々は乗客の安全を守る義務がある
それを放棄することはできない
We're sworn to protect
the passengers of this ship!
I can't go against that!
Even if it kills me!
この命に代えても
Have it your way.
そうしろ
（船長）うおっ！
（操舵士）うわあっ！
ううっ あ…
（ネオン）うーん
実に筋の通ったプロ根性だ
You have the stuff
pros are made of.
I'll preserve you
while you're still beautiful.
美しいまま
全うさせてやろうじゃないか
Don't!!
やめろ！
（銃声）
（ネオン）ハッハッハッハッ！
I've brought the kid.
（手下Ｂ）連れてきました
Go on!
（手下Ｂ）オラ！
Now, now, don't look so grim.
まあ そう険しい顔するな
Sometimes adults have
unhappy differences of opinion.
大人どうしは えてして
悲しくすれ違うものさ
I wanted to ask you how
to steer this huge clunker.
お前に聞きたいのは—
このデカブツの
操舵のしかたについてだ
I don't know the
layout of the console...
（カイト）
コンソールのレイアウトは
分からないけど—
...but you need to regulate the amount
of CO2 sent to the heating plant...
要は発熱プラントに送る
ＣＯ２(ツー)の供給調整と—
...and monitor the
stress on the boiler.
ボイラーにかかる
負荷の管理をするんだ
The light and heat to the hydro plant
also needs to be regulated constantly.
補助的には—
製水プラントへの光熱供給も
見なけりゃならない
Experience is vital.
経験が必要なんだ
Who is this child?!
（船長）何だ？ この子どもは
In other words,
it's a pain in the ass.
つまり
めんどくせえってことだな？
I shouldn't have killed him.
殺(や)るんじゃなかったぜ
Say... Why do you
need the steering?
ねえ 操だって何のためさ
It's been accelerating
kind of funny...
さっきから変に加速してるし
Why don't you just
take the goods and split?
とるものとったら
ずらかればいいじゃないか
'Cause the plan's changed.
予定が変わったのさ
The swag is in a huge safe
in the middle of the ship.
お宝は船の中心部にある大金庫
半端な代物と違う頑丈さだ
It's tougher than
the usual crap.
The worst part of it is, we have
no key unless we go to the city!
ひでえことに 鍵すら
町に行かねえとないときた
Isn't it sad enough
to make you cry?
泣けてくる現実だろ？
おめえなら どうする？
What would you do?
The correct response is:
you crack the whole thing in half.
正解は“丸ごと かち割る” だ！
あ？ どうした
What's wrong?
Do anything you want...
（カイト）勘弁してくれ…
Do anything you want,
but not that!
勘弁してくれよ それだけは！
あ？
You never said you
were going to do that!
そんな話 俺は聞いてねえよ
I was only supposed to silence
the guards and let you inside!
警備を黙らせて—
あんたらを中に引き入れる
だけだったはずだろ？
How come we're wrecking
the whole ship all of a sudden?!
なんで船ごとぶっ壊すなんて
話になんだよ！
That wasn't part of our deal!!
言ってることが
全然違うじゃねえかよ！
うっ！
（カイトの苦しがる声）
Hey, kid.
小僧！
お前 何か勘違いしてねえか
Are you misunderstanding something?
I won the goods on this ship...
襲った獲物のお宝を頂くのに—
...so why do I have
to answer to you...
どうして俺様が てめえに
お伺い立てなきゃならねえんだ！
...before I collect?!
ああ？
（カイト）ぐっ う…
You ain't being beautiful!!
美しくねえんだよ！
If you're going to use
your ship info for a trade...
船の情報をネタに
取り引きすんなら—
...at least prepare
for the worst, stupid!
腹ぐれえくくれえ！ バカー！
（カイト）うえーっ！ ゲホッ
Please...
Anything but the ship!
お願いだ  この船だけは！
ううっ！
Hey, don't be a fool.
Shut up and do what he says!
（手下Ｂ）
おい バカなことは言うな
黙ってヘッドに従え！
Never.
（カイト）イヤだ…
This ship is dad's...
だって この船は…
父さんの…
This is my dad's ship!!!
父さんの船なんだー！
Enough. I'm short-tempered.
もういい　俺は短気なのさ
（カイト）うおっ！
Go pop.
（ネオン）パッと散りな
（電子音）
（手下たち）うわあ！
You okay, squirt? Over here!
（ヴァッシュ）
大丈夫か？ チビ助　こっちだ！
Son of a...
（手下Ｃ）野郎！
Pardon me!
（ヴァッシュ）失礼！
（手下たち）ひゃあああ！
Don't move now,
or you'll get hurt!
（ヴァッシュ）
はいはい 動くとヤバいよ
ん？
（ベラミィ）
ヘッド！ 客室でサムソンが！
Boss! Sampson was
in a passenger cabin!
（ヴァッシュとカイト）
うああああー！
（ヴァッシュ）あ痛(いた)っ！
Ouch!
うん？ 何だ あいつ
What's he supposed to be?
This is going to be fun!
楽しませてくれるぜ
（ネオン）てめえら！
（手下たち）やーっ！
Hey, doggies!
Fetch me a souvenir!
土産を持ってこい！
（手下たち）やーっ！
Make it something
beautifully gorgeous!
美しくてゴージャスなやつだ！
（手下たち）やーっ！
フフフフフフッ
Who is that guy?
誰なんだ あいつは？
（ヴァッシュとカイト）
うっ！ ぐぐぐっ…
もうちょっとマシな助け方
できなかったのかよ！ マジで
Couldn't you think of a better
way to rescue me?! Good grief!
Don't be so picky!
ぜいたく言うなっての
I received more
damage than you!
こっちのほうが
ダメージ デカいんだから
どわあっ！
（ヴァッシュとカイト）
うわあああー！
うひょおおお！
（ヴァッシュとカイトの荒い息）
（カイト）
も… もうちょっと上れば
通風口があるよ
If we climb a little higher,
there's a ventilation shaft.
O-Okay. Let's go.
Let's go NOW.
そうかそうか
今 行こう　すぐ行こう
（手下Ｃ）ん？ 倉庫か
Oh. It's a warehouse.
What'sis?
ん？ 何これ
Trunks?
（手下Ｂ）トランク？
（手下ＢとＣ）うっ！
（殴る音）
Sorry about hitting you
like I did, Captain.
さっきは殴って悪かったな 船長
It looks like I can't control
the ship without your help after all.
結局 あんたに頼らなくちゃ
船は ウマく動かんようだ
So this time, I enlisted a volunteer
from the passengers to help you steer.
今度は あんたが
操縦しやすいように—
乗客の中から有志を募ったよ
（少女）イイイ… イヤー！
No!!
Go to Hell and die,
you scoundrel!!
じ… 地獄に落ちろ
この人でなしめ！
フッ その手の言葉も
言われ飽きたねえ
It gets monotonous
being told to do that.
（少女）イヤッ イヤー！
（船長）くっ ぐぐっ…
見る方向が違うぜ
You're looking in
the wrong direction.
The control lever's over here.
操縦かんは こっちだ
If it's your ship...
あんたの船なら—
...you should be the one
to break it the bad news.
あんたが引導を渡してやるのが
道理だよな
You only have one thing to do.
やることは ただ一つ—
加速だ！
Speed it up.
（少女）イヤー！
Damn!
フハハハハ
ハハハハハハッ
（ヴァッシュ）ハハハハハハッ
（ネオンの高笑い）
♪〜
〜♪
People who sin say this:
（ヴァッシュ）罪を犯す者は言う
That they had to, to survive.
“生きていくために
しかたがなかった”と
People who sin say this:
罪を犯す者は言う
“もう抜け出すことはできない”と
That it's too late to stop.
The shadow called Sin dogs them
steadily without a word.
罪という名の影が—
何も語らずに
ひたひたと付きまとう
Remorse and Agony are repeated,
to finally end up at Despair.
悔恨と苦悩が繰り返され
絶望へと行き着く
But sinners don't know...
だが 罪人は知らないのだ
...that if they turn around,
there is a light...
振り向けば そこに
光があることを
...a light which keeps
shining on them ever so warmly.
こんなにも こんなにも温かく
自分を照らし続けていることを